# Jude Suthagar SUBRAMANIAM

# Operations Professional | Powercoders Participant

Gurtenmundstrasse 9, 6460 Altdorf UR

jude.subramaniam@powercoders.org | +41 77 94 25 109

Date of Birth: 27 October 1977 | Civil status: Married | Residence permit B

GitHub | Learning Blog | LinkedIn

Languages: English (C1), German (B2), Sinhala (B2),

Tamil (mother tongue)

IT skills: Elementary: HTML, CSS, Git, GitHub

Beginner: JavaScript, SQL



#### **PROFILE**

Organized Operation professional with 14 years of experience in the international environment. Managed cross functional activities to ensure fluid and efficient operation. Collaborative team player with strong management, analytical, problem solving, planning and organizational skills. Looking for an internship in the IT industry to develop my career in programming.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

11/2003 - 07/2015

### Operations Officer, UNICEF, Batticaloa, Sri Lanka

The United Nations (UN) mission to Sri Lanka was due to the civil war and Tsunami. The UN mission had more than 10 agencies working in the field. I managed the office operations of one of the UNICEF field offices.

- Carried out basic data/voice network troubleshooting, daily server backup, installation & configuration of network devices and acted as IT Support staff
- Conducted end-user trainings to staff members on ERP and increased the productivity
- Maintained complete database of the office and the warehouse inventories and ensured zero discrepancies
- Efficiently handled a variety of accounting activities, implemented legally adherent and cost-effective procedures and reduced expenses by 17% per year
- Conducted recruitment and provided coaching and appraised job results to supervisees and improved their career development
- Planned and distributed supplies and ensured the timely delivery to the end user

04/2002 - 04/2003

## Technical Assistant, Ministry of Projects & Maintenance, Sohar, Oman

The ministry of P&M maintains the Royal Palaces and I assisted the Director General of Project & Maintenance (DGPM)

- Inspected the ongoing constructions and sent progress reports to the Head Office
- Supervised the Technical staff members and prepared daily work reports
- Effectively managed the office petty cash

01/2000 – 03/2002 Computer Operator, Eastern Self-Reliant Community Awakening

Organization (ESCO), Batticaloa, Sri Lanka

ESCO is a local NGO supporting war affected people in many ways. I mainly created and maintained the office filing system electronically.

- Documented project proposals electronically

- Maintained the records of the credit programs
- Prepared monthly tally sheets and pay abstracts

### **EDUCATION**

09/2020 – 12/2020 Powercoders – Coding Academy for Refugees, Zurich, Switzerland

 Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming
 Weekly business & social skills training (team work, communication, etc.)

 01/2006 – 07/2010 Master of Business Administration, Sikkim Manipal University, India
 01/1998 – 12/1999 National Certificate in Accounting Technician, Technical College,

Sri Lanka

CERTIFICATION

07/2013 – 12/2013 Dynamic Leadership Certificate - Prime, Harvard Business Publishing, NY

2012 **Excelling as Supervisor** – by UNICEF

### **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

04/2017 – present Volunteer Translator, Swiss Red Cross, Altdorf, Switzerland

Supports the Sri Lankan refugees on translations and accompany them to

the Immigration and the hospital appointments.

01/2020 – present Member of the Fire Brigade, Altdorf, Switzerland

01/2019 – present Member, URI Sports Club, Altdorf, Switzerland

Act as event organizer for sports activities and social gatherings.

### **HOBBIES**

Playing Volleyball & Cricket, Cooking and Travelling

### **REFERENCES**

- Hussam Allaham, Powercoders Industry Lead, <a href="https://hussam.allaham@powercoders.org">hussam.allaham@powercoders.org</a>,
  +41 77 906 16 27
- Andrea James, Chief National Committee Relations, UNICEF Geneva, <u>ajames@unicef.org</u>, +41 79 610 84 86
- Christina De Bruin, Deputy Director, UNICEF Office for Relations with EU Institutions, cdebruin@unicef.org, +32 493 40 84 08